# 哇 塞
# （新疆 乌鲁木齐）
Oh wow...
(Urumqi, Xinjiang)
# 看来我也要饿了 感觉
That makes me feel hungry
(Urumqi, Xinjiang)
# （烤包子）
(Roasted buns)
# 刚才司机师傅带我们来的时候
When we were still on the way here with the driver
# 在好远就闻着烤包子的味道
we smelled the scent of the roasted buns at far away
# 他自己都饿了
The driver himself also got hungry
# 看吧 这排队的阵势
Take a look at the line
# 我也不知道要多久才能够吃得上
No idea how long I have to wait to eat
# 烤包子刚端上来就能够闻到一股
As soon as the roasted buns are served, you can smell
# 香味
the scent
# 看看我的烤包子
Look at my roasted buns
# 真的想 赶紧吃掉它
I really want to eat them quickly
# 他这个烤包子
For their roasted buns
# 正面是这个样子的
The front side is like this
# 外面就这种金黄色
Golden brown outside
# 有点掉渣 掉皮的（状态）
The skin is kind of loose
# 反面就是这种带褶皱的
The back side is wrinkled at this
# 闻起来还有羊肉的香味
There's the scent of mutton
# 有点烫
(It's a little hot)
# 之前都是吃的蒸的包子
The buns I used to eat are steamed
# 这次是烤包子
This time, they are roasted
# 把包子放在馕坑里烤着来吃
Buns roasted in a naan oven
# 每一个包子都不算大吧
The buns are not big
# 我们来尝一口
Let's try
# （脆）
(Crispy)
# （包子皮）包子能够吃出来的
You can feel it (the skin)
# 它的皮是用死面擀出来的
The skin is made of unleavened dough
# 因为是死面的
As it's unleavened
# （太厚 口感不好）
# 它的皮擀的特别薄
(Doesn't taste good if too thick)
the skin is extremely thin
# (里面的羊肉)
# 它这个就不能叫肉馅了
(Mutton inside)
It's not quite a "meat stuffing" we call
# 看 都是肉丁
Look, it's all minced meat there
# 里面唯一的菜就是
The only vegetables inside are
# 洋葱 皮芽子
Onion, or "piyazi" (how onions are called in Xinjiang)
# （包子皮）好像一个小帐篷
(The skin) is like a small tent
# 把肉丁 肉团放进去
with mince meat, meatballs put inside
# 它这里面都是大肉块
It's all big chunks of meat
# 吃起来特别得过瘾
which is quite an enjoyment
# 比吃肉馅过瘾的多
Much more enjoyment than having meat stuffings
# 这个包子还有个特点就是
The buns have another characteristic that
# 黑胡椒粉的味道特别重
there's a strong flavor of black pepper powder
# 吃一口感觉好像吃辣椒一样
Bite it and you feel like eating chili
# （辛辣感 重）
(Spiciness: strong)
# 吃烤包子 我还要了一碗酸汤馄饨
To go with the roasted buns, I also ordered a bowl of sour soup wontons
# 每个小馄饨
Each of these little wontons
# 都像一个小元宝一样
looks like a small "yuanbao"
(gold/silver ingot currency used in ancient China)
# 沉入酸汤里
that's lying beneath the sour soup
# 等待着我把它捞起来
awaiting a marine salvage
# 来买烤包子的时候
When we first arrived
# 还是后面的大爷告诉我
it was a grandpa behind who told me that
# 如果说 你要到店里来吃就不需要排队了
if you eat in, you don't need to line up
# 反正也要吃饭嘛 就进来来吃了
Since we were looking for a meal, we just came in
# 免去了排队的烦恼
and avoided the troubles in the line
# 一个多少钱
How much is it for one?
# 3块5一个
3.5 yuan
# 来 给我拿上4个
OK. Can I have four?
# 14块钱
14 yuan
# 这边还有一锅的手抓饭
And there's a wok of pilaf
# 上面都是肉
with a lot of meat
# 还有胡萝卜
and carrots
# 这边吃的都是羊肉
This is place for eating mutton
# 那边还有在串的肉串
Mutton skewers in preparation over there
# 大哥 我问一下 这个店开多久了
Hey bro, how long has the restaurant been open?
# 这个店开多久了
How long has the restaurant been open?
# 10几年了
Over 10 years
# 只是中午卖吗
Does it serve lunches only?
# 早晨9点到下午4点
9am to 4pm
# 这边是刚做出来的
These are freshly made
# 这一炉能够蒸多少个
How many can you make in an oven?
# 哦 烤多少个
I mean, how many can you roast?
# 150个
# 看一直在忙
See, they are busy all the time
# 有 12 个炉子
We have 12 ovens
# 12个炉
12 ovens
# 就这么一直不停地烤
Keep roasting like this
# 一炉出来 一炉进去
One oven out, then one oven in
# 刚出炉的
Freshly roasted buns
# 又来一次
Once again
# 大哥 我问一下 你买了多少个
Hey bro, how many did you buy?
# 10个
# 哦 吃过这个包子
Oh. Have you eaten these buns before?
# 经常吃 我们就在这儿附近住
Pretty often. We live around
# 好多人都跑这边来吃
Many people come here for the buns
# 你要是再晚 可能就排很多人了
If you come later, there might be a very long line
# 现在还属于人少的
It's not very busy now?
# 现在算人少的 到一点多的时候
Not very busy now. When it's 1 o'lock
# 一点多 人多
1 o'clock. It's the busiest
# 现在还属于 人不多的时候
It doesn't count as very busy now
# 这边的烤包子就是出一炉 抢一炉
Every time buns are out of the oven, a battle starts
# 很快就没有了
And they are gone very soon
# 刚才那个大哥说 现在人还不多
The bro said earlier that it's not very busy now
# 半个小时之后 人会更多
It will be busier half an hour later
# 咱们还属于来的比较早的
So we kind of came early
# 关 注 雪 鱼 探 店
(Subscribe)